<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 06:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recent changes</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/changes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/changes/</guid><description> 2023-04-03 - The Noble Lie of Ada Lovelace - First notes for an essay about Ada Lovelace and the myth of her contribution to computer science. 2023-03-19 - Semantic markup and sidenotes - Realised I&amp;rsquo;d misunderstood the guidance for &amp;lt;article&amp;gt;, rejigged the markup to comply; adjusted the CSS for sidenotes</description></item><item><title>Links</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/links/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/links/</guid><description>Haecceity or &amp;rsquo;thisness'
The Bibites by The Bibites An attempt at creating real digital life
The film, &amp;lsquo;Danton&amp;rsquo; one of those I caught by chance on TV and couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop watching. Depardieu as Danton
Charles, not Ada A well-intenioned untruth but an untruth nonetheless. May write about this
The supposed destruction of classical temples and documents by Christians is a simplistic myth
Diegetic music or source music is music in a drama (e.</description></item><item><title>About this website</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently revamped this website and I&amp;rsquo;ll be using it to collect links and content I find interesting, and for my own occasional writing, so the important things are speed and readability. I&amp;rsquo;ve closely followed the suggestions of Edward Tufte&amp;rsquo;s stylesheet recommendations for simple and clear text on the web, and a long-standing aim is that markup should be as close to purely semantic as possible. The principles derived by Dave Liepmann from Tufte&amp;rsquo;s writings are guidelines, not mandatory diktats, but they&amp;rsquo;re very useful guidelines.</description></item><item><title>The noble lie of Ada Lovelace</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/adalovelace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/adalovelace/</guid><description>Despite Ada Lovelace Day, the Ada Lovelace Institute, the Ada Lovelace Award and Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s confirmation that Ada Lovelace is &amp;lsquo;often regarded as the first computer programmer&amp;rsquo;, Lovelace was not the first programmer and she had no hand in the creation of the Babbage Difference Engine and Analytic Engine. Does the exaggeration of her contribution matter? Is it a noble lie? Not only is there no evidence that Lovelace ever prepared a program for the Analytical Engine, but her correspondence with Babbage shows that she did not have the knowledge to do so.</description></item><item><title>Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/poetry/seeingoffyuan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/poetry/seeingoffyuan/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying my hand at translating Tang-era poems again. This one&amp;rsquo;s by Wang Wei
Original in traditional script
And here&amp;rsquo;s my translation:
Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi
The willows at the inn are fresh and green The dust is dampened by the morning dew I buy my friend another cup of wine Beyond Yang Pass, good wine and friends are few &amp;mdash; Wang Wei, 8th C</description></item><item><title>The Best Metaphor</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/thebestmetaphor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/thebestmetaphor/</guid><description>A small group of almost-naked figures gathers at the edge of a rectangular jungle clearing. At the northern end stands their recently-completed spindly bamboo mast; halfway along one of the longer sides is a rickety hut on thin stilts. Running down the center of the cleared area, a strip of flattened sandy scrub, like a giants&amp;rsquo; cricket pitch. Twenty metres beyond the southern end of the clearing, through the jungle greenery, is a strand of white sand, and then the sea.</description></item><item><title>The Banach-Tarski Paradox</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/stem/banachtarski/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/stem/banachtarski/</guid><description>Given a solid ball in 3‑dimensional space, there exists a decomposition of the ball into a finite number of disjoint subsets, which can then be put back together in a different way to yield two identical copies of the original ball.The reassembly process involves only moving the pieces around and rotating them without changing their shape.
The Banach-Tarski Paradox
This &amp;lsquo;paradox&amp;rsquo; is a firm result in set theory. It&amp;rsquo;s not up for debate.</description></item><item><title>Pronouncing Don Quixote in La Mancha</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/donquixote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/donquixote/</guid><description>Pizarro in the market square of Trujillo, Spain
On holiday in Spain in 2007 I read Don Quixote — and ploughing through some parts in the Don’s homeland, the region of La Mancha, I thought I’d solved the puzzle of the protagonist’s name: Key-Ho-Tay or Kwiksot?
I’ve previously spoken the name ‘Don Quixote’ as Don Key-ho-tay, presuming it was more Spanish, though of course I’ve been aware of the alternative inEnglish of Don Quick-Sot.</description></item></channel></rss>