<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>japan on The website of David Jones</title><link>http://askdavidjones.com/tags/japan/</link><description>Recent content in japan on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://askdavidjones.com/tags/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Haiku Trial</title><link>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/04/haikutrial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/04/haikutrial/</guid><description>Mother and two children, Tokyo. Sketched on a business trip last year
I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few haiku, that quintessentially Japanese verse form.
Just one point: in the West we think of the metre of haiku as being simply 5 &amp;ndash; 7 &amp;ndash; 5 syllables. In fact the most common form is 5 &amp;ndash; 7 &amp;ndash; 5 morae, where a mora is &amp;lsquo;a unit in phonology that determines syllable weight&amp;rsquo;. If that&amp;rsquo;s not clear, try: &amp;lsquo;something of which a long syllable consists of two and a short syllable consists of one&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Isabella Bird</title><link>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/04/isabellabird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/04/isabellabird/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m reading a book about Japan by the remarkable Isabella Bird.
Isabella Bird
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember ever caring much about travel writing when I was younger but, coinciding with my own travelling further afield, I&amp;rsquo;ve read more of it. Theroux, naturally, and Thubron; but also older efforts, like Thesiger, Robert Byron, Eric Newby. And going way back I really enjoy travel writing from a time when it was unusual-to-near-impossible to make the journeys made, where travelling was exploring.</description></item><item><title>Land of the...</title><link>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/03/landofthe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 17:00:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/03/landofthe/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m learning Japanese, starting with two of their three writing systems, hirigana and katakana. The third writing system that I haven&amp;rsquo;t started with yet is the Chinese character inspired kanji, though I did learn a little traditional Chinese script a few years ago. Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun thing I&amp;rsquo;ve only just discovered.
The kanji for &amp;lsquo;Japan&amp;rsquo; (Nihon/Nippon)
So the issue of the correct name for Japan isn&amp;rsquo;t simple. You&amp;rsquo;ll usually hear the kanji, above, pronounced either &amp;lsquo;Nihon&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Nippon&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Sketching in Japan</title><link>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/03/sketchinginjapan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/03/sketchinginjapan/</guid><description>Two schoolchildren, Tokyo
Although I was working most of the time when I visited Japan last year I did manage to pop in to a couple of excellent museums and I spent some snatched moments taking a few photographs and doing a spot of sketching.
Hence this quick drawing I did in the street, walking down towards Tokyo Tower and the Zojoji Temple. It&amp;rsquo;s not in my usual style but I was aiming for a sort of Japanese vernacular - think Hergé out of Hasui Kawase.</description></item><item><title>Japanese for 'bottom'</title><link>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/03/bottom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/03/bottom/</guid><description>Toilet controls on my Japanese toilet
My new ability to read hirigana means I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to decipher, for the first time, the instructions to my hotel toilet in Tokyo last year.
The middle row in the photo has the hirigana おしり: O &amp;ndash; Shi &amp;ndash; Ri. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t speak much Japanese yet so I did have to look up oshiri. And it means&amp;hellip; bottom.
That figures.</description></item><item><title>I think I'm learning Japanese</title><link>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/01/learningjapanese/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://askdavidjones.com/blog/2018/01/learningjapanese/</guid><description>A moment ago my phone sent me an alert to tell me that it was time to revise my Japanese. The app, LingoDeer, thinks I could do with practising my Katakana - and it&amp;rsquo;s not allowing me to move on with my vocabulary until it&amp;rsquo;s satisfied with my progress. The slightly dispiritng progress tracker tells me I&amp;rsquo;m 1.1% through the training.
Last year I went to Japan to kick off a software project that will be rolled-out around the world.</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Japanese words to learn</title><link>http://askdavidjones.com/projects/japan/japanesetop10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>http://askdavidjones.com/projects/japan/japanesetop10/</guid><description>SUMIMASEN (PRONOUNCED: “SUE-ME-MAH-SEN”) The closest English translation would be “excuse me”, but sumimasen is a phrase that can be used for many things including “sorry”, “thanks” and as an introduction before asking a question. If you bump into someone it’s polite to say a quick sumimasen, but it can also be used if you’re trying to get someone’s attention or before taking something you were offered.
WAKARIMASEN (PRONOUNCED: “WAH-KAH-REE-MAH-SEN”) It’s important to indicate that you do not understand something.</description></item></channel></rss>