<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>art on The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/art/</link><description>Recent content in art on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 21:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sketching</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/sketching/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 21:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/sketching/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying to evolve a dependable, repeatable sketching style for my trip to Japan, where I&amp;rsquo;ll be attempting to make quite a few drawings as we travel around.
Pagoda in Beijing&amp;rsquo;s Summer Palace, from my visit there a couple of years ago
I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought that anyone can be taught to draw. For Victorian ladies and gentlemen, who were taught to sketch, and sketch competently, it was virtually a sine qua non of being civilised.</description></item><item><title>Vermeer Burger</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/vermeerburger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 09:00:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/vermeerburger/</guid><description>Vermeer and burgers
I don&amp;rsquo;t have a very well thought-through aesthetics though I do tend towards the view that, in some sense and to some degree, there are objective standards of beauty. David Deutsch has a very interesting chapter on this in, &amp;lsquo;The Beginning of Infinity&amp;rsquo;, and he concludes that the argument there cannot be objective aesthetic standards is a relic of empiricism; that there are in fact aesthetic truths.</description></item><item><title>Sketching in Japan</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/sketchinginjapan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/sketchinginjapan/</guid><description>Two schoolchildren, Tokyo
Although I was working most of the time when I visited Japan last year I did manage to pop in to a couple of excellent museums and I spent some snatched moments taking a few photographs and doing a spot of sketching.
Hence this quick drawing I did in the street, walking down towards Tokyo Tower and the Zojoji Temple. It&amp;rsquo;s not in my usual style but I was aiming for a sort of Japanese vernacular - think Hergé out of Hasui Kawase.</description></item></channel></rss>