<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 16:19:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CV - David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/resume/cv/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/resume/cv/</guid><description>&lt;section class="profsumm">
&lt;h2 id="professional-summary">Professional Summary&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Experienced in designing and implementing complex solutions across multiple industries, nationally and internationally.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Possesses strong technical expertise and excellent communication skills.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Able to translate business requirements effectively into technical solutions that meet or exceed client expectations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Experienced in managing large transformation projects, cloud migrations, and legacy update programs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Possess strong leadership qualities and can guide teams in achieving project goals.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provide architectural leadership to ensure project success.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proficient in team management, including assigning tasks, setting goals, and ensuring deadlines are met.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Adaptable and able to work collaboratively with cross-functional teams to achieve common goals.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Up-to-date with emerging technologies and industry trends to ensure solutions remain innovative and effective.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="skills">Skills&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Expertise in solution architecture, design, and implementation&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Extensive knowledge of cloud technologies (AWS, Azure, GCP)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Strong understanding of software development life cycle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ability to create technical documentation and presentations&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Excellent communication and interpersonal skills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Proven leadership and project management skills&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/section>
&lt;section class="experience">
&lt;h2 id="recent-employment-experience">Recent Employment Experience&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="senior-solutions-architect-capgemini">Senior Solutions Architect, Capgemini&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="march-2018--present">March 2018 – Present&lt;/h4>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Led the design and implementation of complex solutions for large transformation projects for key clients.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Seconded to large Government department to provide architectural guidance and leadership&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Designed complex cloud-based solutions and closely collaborated with AWS and IBM to evolve new product offerings&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Translated business requirements into technical solutions that meet client expectations.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provided guidance to project teams throughout the development life cycle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Collaborated with stakeholders, including project managers, developers, and business analysts, to ensure successful project delivery.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Created technical documentation and presentations to communicate solution design and implementation details to clients and project teams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Conducted technical evaluations of third-party products to ensure they meet client needs.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Developed and delivered technical training to internal and external teams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Provided technical support to clients during and after solution implementation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reviewer for more junior architects&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Board member of internal Architect Academy training scheme - mentoring &amp;amp; training junior team members on solution architecture and design best practices.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>On working group for exploration on AI/LLMs. Also, producing content for the Capgemini Streams platform&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/poetry/seeingoffyuan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/poetry/seeingoffyuan/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying my hand at translating Tang-era poems again. This one&amp;rsquo;s by Wang Wei&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="figimg">&lt;img src="http://www.chinese-poems.com/yuant.gif"
 alt="Original in traditional script"/>&lt;span class="figcaption">
 &lt;p>Original in traditional script&lt;/p>
 &lt;/span>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>And here&amp;rsquo;s my translation:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote class="poetry">
&lt;p class="poemtitle">Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi&lt;/p>&lt;pre>
The willows at the inn are fresh and green
The dust is dampened by the morning dew
I buy my friend another cup of wine
Beyond Yang Pass, good wine and friends are few
&lt;/pre>&lt;footer>&amp;mdash; Wang Wei, 8th C&lt;/footer>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>The Best Metaphor</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/thebestmetaphor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/thebestmetaphor/</guid><description>&lt;div class="epigraph" >
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A small group of almost-naked figures gathers at the edge of a rectangular jungle clearing. At the northern end stands their recently-completed spindly bamboo mast; halfway along one of the longer sides is a rickety hut on thin stilts. Running down the center of the cleared area, a strip of flattened sandy scrub, like a giants&amp;rsquo; cricket pitch. Twenty metres beyond the southern end of the clearing, through the jungle greenery, is a strand of white sand, and then the sea.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Banach-Tarski Paradox</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/stem/banachtarski/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/stem/banachtarski/</guid><description>&lt;section >
&lt;p>Given a solid ball in 3‑dimensional space, there exists a decomposition of the ball into a finite number of disjoint subsets, which can then be put back together in a different way to yield two identical copies of the original ball.The reassembly process involves only moving the pieces around and rotating them without changing their shape.&lt;/p>
&lt;figure class="figimg">&lt;a href="https://c1.staticflickr.com/5/4776/39142320020_db99fb7161_z.jpg">&lt;img src="https://c1.staticflickr.com/5/4776/39142320020_db99fb7161_z.jpg"
 alt="The Banach-Tarski Paradox"/>&lt;/a>&lt;span class="figcaption">
 &lt;p>The Banach-Tarski Paradox&lt;/p>
 &lt;/span>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>This &amp;lsquo;paradox&amp;rsquo; is a firm result in set theory. It&amp;rsquo;s not up for debate.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pronouncing Don Quixote in La Mancha</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/donquixote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/donquixote/</guid><description>&lt;section >
&lt;figure class="figimg">&lt;a href="https://c2.staticflickr.com/2/1086/1094901272_e033158971.jpg">&lt;img src="https://c2.staticflickr.com/2/1086/1094901272_e033158971.jpg"
 alt="Pizarro in the market square of Trujillo, Spain"/>&lt;/a>&lt;span class="figcaption">
 &lt;p>Pizarro in the market square of Trujillo, Spain&lt;/p>
 &lt;/span>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;p>On holiday in Spain in 2007 I read &lt;em>Don Quixote&lt;/em> — and ploughing through some parts in the Don’s homeland, the region of La Mancha, I thought I’d solved the puzzle of the protagonist’s name: &lt;em>Key-Ho-Tay&lt;/em> or &lt;em>Kwiksot&lt;/em>?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ve previously spoken the name ‘Don Quixote’ as Don &lt;em>Key-ho-tay&lt;/em>, presuming it was more Spanish, though of course I’ve been aware of the alternative inEnglish of Don &lt;em>Quick-Sot&lt;/em>. The version of the novel I had, the translation by John Rutherford (winner of the 2002 Primo Valle Inclàn Prize) definitely plumps for &lt;em>Kwiksot&lt;/em> in its rhymes. For example, on page 222 (Chapter XXVI) of the paperback, he translates a poem to read:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>