<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 06:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2022/08/seeingoffyuan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2022/08/seeingoffyuan/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying my hand at translating Tang-era poems again. This one&amp;rsquo;s by Wang Wei
Original in traditional script
And here&amp;rsquo;s my translation:
Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi
Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi
The willows at the inn are fresh and green
The dust is dampened by the morning dew
I buy my friend another cup of wine
Beyond Yang Pass, good wine and friends are few — Wang Wei, 8th C</description></item><item><title>Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2022/08/seeingoffyuan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2022/08/seeingoffyuan/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying my hand at translating Tang-era poems again. This one&amp;rsquo;s by Wang Wei
Original poem in traditional script
And here&amp;rsquo;s my translation:
Seeing off Yuan the Second on a Mission to Anxi
The willows at the inn are fresh and green The dust is dampened by the morning dew I buy my friend another cup of wine Beyond Yang Pass, good wine and friends are few &amp;mdash; Wang Wei, 8th C</description></item><item><title>Bindicator - an Alexa skill for bin collections</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/06/bindicate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/06/bindicate/</guid><description>A Glasgow-based IT consultant who developed a little bin-shaped device that lights-up with different colours to indicate which bins are due for collection prompted me to do something similar with Alexa and AWS lambdas. It’s essentially free, and free is good.
Introduction Can’t remember which bins to put out? This is a quick look at an Alexa skill I’ve developed that uses my local council’s website as a source of information about bin collections, and lets me ask Alexa when my next bin collection is, and what bins are being collected, and when any particular bin is next being collected.</description></item><item><title>Learning Languages the Schliemann way</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/05/schliemann/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/05/schliemann/</guid><description>Heinrich Schliemann bucked contemporary opinion in the 19th Century and, taking Homer seriously, uncovered Troy - sort of - and ‘gazed on the face of Agamemmnon at Mycenae. Again, sort of.
Schliemann’s largely excoriated today for his methods, showmanship, sharp practice, and wild claims about the pre-classical Mediterranean. I think it’s futile to judge the past by today’s standards – I think Schliemann was a great man, warts and all.</description></item><item><title>Business Facades and Potemkin Villages</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/05/potemkin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/05/potemkin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Best Metaphor</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/05/thebestmetaphor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/05/thebestmetaphor/</guid><description>A small group of almost-naked figures gathers at the edge of a rectangular jungle clearing. At the northern end stands their recently-completed spindly bamboo mast; halfway along one of the longer sides is a rickety hut on thin stilts. Running down the center of the cleared area, a strip of flattened sandy scrub, like a giants&amp;rsquo; cricket pitch. Twenty metres beyond the southern end of the clearing, through the jungle greenery, is a strand of white sand, and then the sea.</description></item><item><title>Haiku Trial</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/haikutrial/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/haikutrial/</guid><description>Mother and two children, Tokyo. Sketched on a business trip last year
I&amp;rsquo;ve written a few haiku, that quintessentially Japanese verse form.
Just one point: in the West we think of the metre of haiku as being simply 5 &amp;ndash; 7 &amp;ndash; 5 syllables. In fact the most common form is 5 &amp;ndash; 7 &amp;ndash; 5 morae, where a mora is &amp;lsquo;a unit in phonology that determines syllable weight&amp;rsquo;. If that&amp;rsquo;s not clear, try: &amp;lsquo;something of which a long syllable consists of two and a short syllable consists of one&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>Isabella Bird</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/isabellabird/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/isabellabird/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m reading a book about Japan by the remarkable Isabella Bird.
Isabella Bird
I don&amp;rsquo;t remember ever caring much about travel writing when I was younger but, coinciding with my own travelling further afield, I&amp;rsquo;ve read more of it. Theroux, naturally, and Thubron; but also older efforts, like Thesiger, Robert Byron, Eric Newby. And going way back I really enjoy travel writing from a time when it was unusual-to-near-impossible to make the journeys made, where travelling was exploring.</description></item><item><title>The Unbearable Lightness of Being on Social Media</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/unbearablelightness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/unbearablelightness/</guid><description>The memory throws up high and dry A crowd of twisted things; &amp;mdash; Eliot, 'Rhapsody on a Windy Night' Vicky Lai&amp;rsquo;s recent blog post about deleting older tweets, using an AWS lambda, struck a deep chord with me and I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented her ephemeral solution. Description of technical fix over at Vicky&amp;rsquo;s blog and my take on it below.
Vicky believes that social media imposes a view of identity that&amp;rsquo;s new &amp;ndash; and innacurate.</description></item><item><title>A little network issue</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/network/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/network/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with cheap-and-cheerful voice control of my music system. I have a NAS with tens of thousands of ripped music files and I&amp;rsquo;d like to play them, easily, on my Sonos speakers and/or my Echo Dots.
The salient bits of my home network
Now I could upload them to some subscription service, and use the streaming capabilities - but it seems to me a bad idea for three reasons:</description></item><item><title>Klee's Line</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/kleesline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/kleesline/</guid><description>Paul Klee called drawing, &amp;lsquo;Taking a line for a walk&amp;rsquo; and ever since I first saw his drawings I&amp;rsquo;ve been really taken with the quality of his line.
Paul Klee, &amp;lsquo;They&amp;rsquo;re Biting&amp;rsquo;
I just assumed he&amp;rsquo;d drawn in ink on &amp;ndash; possibly&amp;ndash; damp paper, which I thought would explain the bleeding of the line and it&amp;rsquo;s smudginess. I tried to mimic it again and again, with scratchy-nibbed dip-pens, different weights and finishes of paper; and I never got there.</description></item><item><title>Pomostmodern murder</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/pomomurder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/pomomurder/</guid><description>I once complained to the small clique in control of a student magazine that they&amp;rsquo;d devoted an entire issue to semiological analyses of, variously, clothes, cinema and music. &amp;ldquo;And have you actually read anything about semiology?&amp;rdquo; sneered one?
I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really and the criticism smarted so I went off to learn about semiology. And then postmodernism. I quite liked some Roland Barthes. I read Jonathan Culler on deconstruction &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;On Deconstruction&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; and I read Derrida, and Baudrillard, and de Man, and Foucault, and Lacan, and more.</description></item><item><title>Sacrifice to the Cat that Scared all the Rats</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/fivewhitecat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/fivewhitecat/</guid><description>The Tang dynasty (618-906 AD), and in part the succeeding Song dynasty, are considered a Golden Age for Chinese Art and Poetry. For example, take a look at this painting of a bird by Li Anzhong, early-mid 1100s.
Bird on a Branch by Li Anzhong
And this is typical, and unremarkable, and just one example of thousands of beautiful paintings from the period. As for the poetry, I read a fair amount of it before I went to China a few years back.</description></item><item><title>The Star Trek Killing Machine</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/startrekkilling/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/startrekkilling/</guid><description>In his book, &amp;lsquo;Reasons and Persons&amp;rsquo; (sometimes called &amp;rsquo; the most significant work of moral philosophy since the 1800s&amp;rsquo;), the philosopher Derek Parfit indulged his readers with several amusing thought experiments.
In Part 3 - Personal Identity, for example, he considers a Star Trek-like matter transporter. Imagine, he writes, a scanner here on Earth that &amp;lsquo;reads&amp;rsquo; the complete state of all the cells of your body, and in the process destroys them and transmits the information to a receiving station on Mars, where a Replicator will construct an exact copy of you, with all your memories.</description></item><item><title>Sketching</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/sketching/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 21:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/sketching/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying to evolve a dependable, repeatable sketching style for my trip to Japan, where I&amp;rsquo;ll be attempting to make quite a few drawings as we travel around.
Pagoda in Beijing&amp;rsquo;s Summer Palace, from my visit there a couple of years ago
I&amp;rsquo;ve always thought that anyone can be taught to draw. For Victorian ladies and gentlemen, who were taught to sketch, and sketch competently, it was virtually a sine qua non of being civilised.</description></item><item><title>World Poetry Day</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/worldpoetryday/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 17:00:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/worldpoetryday/</guid><description>A belated post catching up on World Poetry Day. Here are two nominations, both inspired by Ancient Greece, the first contemporary and the second around 2,000 years old.
Alice Oswald, Memorial My most recent discovery and keeper has been Alice Oswald - especially &amp;lsquo;Memorial&amp;rsquo;, a retelling of the Iliad with only the deaths left in. She was trained as a classicist and sometimes calls this a translation, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s an original work inspired by Homer.</description></item><item><title>Land of the...</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/landofthe/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 17:00:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/landofthe/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m learning Japanese, starting with two of their three writing systems, hirigana and katakana. The third writing system that I haven&amp;rsquo;t started with yet is the Chinese character inspired kanji, though I did learn a little traditional Chinese script a few years ago. Here&amp;rsquo;s a fun thing I&amp;rsquo;ve only just discovered.
The kanji for &amp;lsquo;Japan&amp;rsquo; (Nihon/Nippon)
So the issue of the correct name for Japan isn&amp;rsquo;t simple. You&amp;rsquo;ll usually hear the kanji, above, pronounced either &amp;lsquo;Nihon&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;Nippon&amp;rsquo;.</description></item><item><title>The Banach-Tarski Paradox</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/banachtarski/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/banachtarski/</guid><description>Given a solid ball in 3‑dimensional space, there exists a decomposition of the ball into a finite number of disjoint subsets, which can then be put back together in a different way to yield two identical copies of the original ball.The reassembly process involves only moving the pieces around and rotating them without changing their shape.
The Banach-Tarski Paradox
This &amp;lsquo;paradox&amp;rsquo; is a firm result in set theory. It&amp;rsquo;s not up for debate.</description></item><item><title>Vermeer Burger</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/vermeerburger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 09:00:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/vermeerburger/</guid><description>Vermeer and burgers
I don&amp;rsquo;t have a very well thought-through aesthetics though I do tend towards the view that, in some sense and to some degree, there are objective standards of beauty. David Deutsch has a very interesting chapter on this in, &amp;lsquo;The Beginning of Infinity&amp;rsquo;, and he concludes that the argument there cannot be objective aesthetic standards is a relic of empiricism; that there are in fact aesthetic truths.</description></item><item><title>The Madness of Crowds</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/crowdmadness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 06:00:07 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/crowdmadness/</guid><description>Charles Mackay’s classic &amp;lsquo;Extraordinary Popular Delusions and the Madness of Crowds&amp;rsquo; touches on bizarre beliefs shared by relatively large numbers of people. Then there are the psychoses shared on a smaller scale - the folie à deux, a syndrome where delusional beliefs may be shared with another person – or, more generally, the folie à plusieurs, known to DSM as the Shared Psychotic Disorder.
A startling example of the folie à deux is that of the twins Ursula and Sabina Eriksson who, among other things, deliberately and repeatedly hurled themselves in front of motorway traffic</description></item><item><title>Sketching in Japan</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/sketchinginjapan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/sketchinginjapan/</guid><description>Two schoolchildren, Tokyo
Although I was working most of the time when I visited Japan last year I did manage to pop in to a couple of excellent museums and I spent some snatched moments taking a few photographs and doing a spot of sketching.
Hence this quick drawing I did in the street, walking down towards Tokyo Tower and the Zojoji Temple. It&amp;rsquo;s not in my usual style but I was aiming for a sort of Japanese vernacular - think Hergé out of Hasui Kawase.</description></item><item><title>Pi Day: estimating pi with Monte Carlo simulations</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/piday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/piday/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s Pi Day (because of the weird American date convention of m.d.y the date is 3.14 in the US). So for Pi Day I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at Monte Carlo simulations in R. Here&amp;rsquo;s the result of a simple simulation of pi.
Four simulation runs to estimate pi with an increasing number of iterations
Four runs, the first with 1,000 iterations; the second with 10,000; the third with 100,000, the fourth with 1,000,000.</description></item><item><title>Pi Day: estimating pi with Monte Carlo simulations</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/piday/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/piday/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s Pi Day (because of the weird American date convention of m.d.y the date is 3.14 in the US). So for Pi Day I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at Monte Carlo simulations in R. Here&amp;rsquo;s the result of a simple simulation of pi.
Four simulation runs to estimate pi with an increasing number of iterations
Four runs, the first with 1,000 iterations; the second with 10,000; the third with 100,000, the fourth with 1,000,000.</description></item><item><title>Ancient Greek literature: it's really rather good</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/ancientgreeklit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/ancientgreeklit/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a longtime fan of the Iliad &amp;ndash; I think one of my old primary school teachers must have read a version to my class when I was an infant because I seem to have known the stories forever. The judgement of Paris, the elopement of Helen, the becalming of the Greek ships and the sacrifice of Iphignia, and so on. I have listened, rapt, to an hour-long lecture devoted to the very first line:</description></item><item><title>Japanese for 'bottom'</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/bottom/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/bottom/</guid><description>Toilet controls on my Japanese toilet
My new ability to read hirigana means I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to decipher, for the first time, the instructions to my hotel toilet in Tokyo last year.
The middle row in the photo has the hirigana おしり: O &amp;ndash; Shi &amp;ndash; Ri. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t speak much Japanese yet so I did have to look up oshiri. And it means&amp;hellip; bottom.
That figures.</description></item><item><title>Benefits of randomness</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/01/randombenefits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/01/randombenefits/</guid><description>Delph, where the Pythia babbled her prophecies
The Greeks at Delphi used the ravings of a priestess possibly high on methane and ethanol to make famously ambiguous predictions. Ancient Rome used sacred chickens and the innards of slaughtered animals. Other historical methods of divination include:
pyromancy (by fire) ophiomancy (by snakes) pegomancy (by spring water) anemoscopy (by wind) daphnomancy (by burning laurel wreaths) hippomancy (by horses) tiromancy (by cheese) Way out East, Ancient China used the patterns made by throwing yarrow stalks to the ground as a starting point for cleromancy using the I Ching.</description></item><item><title>I think I'm learning Japanese</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/01/learningjapanese/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/01/learningjapanese/</guid><description>A moment ago my phone sent me an alert to tell me that it was time to revise my Japanese. The app, LingoDeer, thinks I could do with practising my Katakana - and it&amp;rsquo;s not allowing me to move on with my vocabulary until it&amp;rsquo;s satisfied with my progress. The slightly dispiritng progress tracker tells me I&amp;rsquo;m 1.1% through the training.
Last year I went to Japan to kick off a software project that will be rolled-out around the world.</description></item><item><title>Chernoff Faces and crime data</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2017/01/chernoff/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2017/01/chernoff/</guid><description>Chernoff faces represent multivariate data as different aspects of cartoon faces, relying on the brain&amp;rsquo;s powerful face-processing abilities to highlight oddities.
The principle is that we&amp;rsquo;ve evolved with a particularly powerful set of cognitive processes that analyse faces, because they&amp;rsquo;re so important to us; so if we can represent variations in data as changes in faces, our powerful face-processing systems should spot anomalies.
This is my attempt using R for processing, on various crime-data axes for all the states in the US to see if anything leaps out.</description></item><item><title>Pronouncing Don Quixote in La Mancha</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2016/11/donquixote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2016/11/donquixote/</guid><description>Pizarro in the market square of Trujillo, Spain
On holiday in Spain in 2007 I read Don Quixote — and ploughing through some parts in the Don’s homeland, the region of La Mancha, I thought I’d solved the puzzle of the protagonist’s name: Key-Ho-Tay or Kwiksot?
I’ve previously spoken the name ‘Don Quixote’ as Don Key-ho-tay although of course I’ve been aware of the alternative Don Quick-Sot. The version of the novel I had, the translation by John Rutherford (winner of the 2002 Primo Valle Inclàn Prize) definitely plumps for Kwiksot in its rhymes.</description></item><item><title>Respository activity visualised</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2015/11/repovisualised/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2015/11/repovisualised/</guid><description>My development team being busy. Visualisation of Git repo commits using Gource.
This represents Git-commit activity over time on a large codebase by my development team, who were working on an AWS telemetry solution.</description></item><item><title>Top 10 Japanese words to learn</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/projects/japan/japanesetop10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/projects/japan/japanesetop10/</guid><description>SUMIMASEN (PRONOUNCED: “SUE-ME-MAH-SEN”) The closest English translation would be “excuse me”, but sumimasen is a phrase that can be used for many things including “sorry”, “thanks” and as an introduction before asking a question. If you bump into someone it’s polite to say a quick sumimasen, but it can also be used if you’re trying to get someone’s attention or before taking something you were offered.
WAKARIMASEN (PRONOUNCED: “WAH-KAH-REE-MAH-SEN”) It’s important to indicate that you do not understand something.</description></item></channel></rss>