<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Articles on The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/categories/articles/</link><description>Recent content in Articles on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 15:47:13 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/categories/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bayesian Thinking</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/bayesianepistemology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/bayesianepistemology/</guid><description>The death of Mike Lynch and others on board his yacht &amp;lsquo;Bayesian&amp;rsquo; got me thinking about Bayes Theorem and its use as a tool in knowledge discovery. Bayes Theorem - the basics Stephen Hawking said he was once told that the inclusion of each equation in his book would cut the number of interested readers by 50%. Nevertheless, this one isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to grasp though it might appear to be using slightly odd syntax if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen how conditional probabilities are expressed.</description></item><item><title>Getting married in Japan</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/japanesemarriage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/japanesemarriage/</guid><description>I’m a UK citizen, and I recently married another UK citizen in Tokyo while we were on holiday. If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to do the same, here’s a detailed guide to help you through the process. It will involve the preparation of some translations before you travel, a trip to the British Embassy in Tokyo (pre-booked), and at least one visit to a municpal office in Japan that deals with the registration of births, marriages, deaths, and divorces &amp;mdash; I recommend two visits.</description></item><item><title>The noble lie of Ada Lovelace</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/adalovelace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/adalovelace/</guid><description>Despite Ada Lovelace Day, the Ada Lovelace Institute, the Ada Lovelace Award and Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s confirmation that Ada Lovelace is &amp;lsquo;often regarded as the first computer programmer&amp;rsquo;, Lovelace was not the first programmer and she had no hand in the creation of the Babbage Difference Engine and Analytic Engine. Does the exaggeration of her contribution matter? Is it a noble lie? Not only is there no evidence that Lovelace ever prepared a program for the Analytical Engine, but her correspondence with Babbage shows that she did not have the knowledge to do so.</description></item></channel></rss>