<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 17:16:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Quantum Path to Improbability</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/quantumimmortality/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/quantumimmortality/</guid><description>&lt;p>In the vast landscape of quantum mechanics, few interpretations have captured the imagination quite like Hugh Everett III&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>Many Worlds&lt;/em> approach. This interpretation suggests that quantum events spawn multiple branches of reality, with each possible outcome manifesting in its own universe. The implications of this become extraordinary when we consider the nature of probability across an infinite number of universe branches.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consider a simple quantum event: a particle that could decay or not decay in a given moment. In the Many Worlds interpretation, both outcomes occur, creating two branches of reality. Now extend this to the countless quantum events occurring in every atom of your body, every second of every day. The number of branches multiplies exponentially, creating an unfathomable number of parallel realities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bayesian Thinking</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/bayesianepistemology/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/bayesianepistemology/</guid><description>&lt;div class="pagedescription">The death of Mike Lynch and others on board his yacht &amp;lsquo;Bayesian&amp;rsquo; got me thinking about Bayes Theorem and its use as a tool in knowledge discovery.&lt;/div>
&lt;section >
&lt;h2 id="bayes-theorem----the-basics">Bayes Theorem - the basics&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Stephen Hawking said he was once told that the inclusion of each equation in his book would cut the number of interested readers by 50%. Nevertheless, this one isn&amp;rsquo;t hard to grasp though it might appear to be using slightly odd syntax if you haven&amp;rsquo;t seen how conditional probabilities are expressed.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The noble lie of Ada Lovelace</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/adalovelace/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/adalovelace/</guid><description>&lt;div class="pagedescription">Despite 
&lt;a href="https://findingada.com/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" class="external">Ada Lovelace Day&lt;/a>, the 
&lt;a href="https://www.adalovelaceinstitute.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank" class="external">Ada Lovelace Institute&lt;/a>, the 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace_Award" rel="noopener" target="_blank" class="external" data-link-icon="wikipedia" data-link-icon-type="svg">Ada Lovelace Award&lt;/a> and Wikipedia&amp;rsquo;s confirmation that Ada Lovelace is 
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace" rel="noopener" target="_blank" class="external" data-link-icon="wikipedia" data-link-icon-type="svg">&amp;lsquo;often regarded as the first computer programmer&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a>, Lovelace was not the first programmer and she had no hand in the creation of the Babbage Difference Engine and Analytic Engine. Does the exaggeration of her contribution matter? Is it a noble lie?&lt;/div>
&lt;section >
 &lt;div class="sidenote">&lt;div class="sidenotecontents">
 &lt;blockquote>&lt;p>Not only is there no evidence that Lovelace ever prepared a program for the Analytical Engine, but her correspondence with Babbage shows that she did not have the knowledge to do so.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>