<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Japan on The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/japan/</link><description>Recent content in Japan on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 17:16:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Mathematical Framework for Understanding Shinto</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/categoricalshinto/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/categoricalshinto/</guid><description>&lt;div class="pagedescription">&lt;p>Japan&amp;rsquo;s native religion of Shinto presents a fascinating paradox to religious scholars. Its apparent contradictions — ancient yet modern, polytheistic yet philosophically abstract, deeply ritualistic yet fluid — have long resisted Western attempts at categorisation. Traditional religious frameworks, with their emphasis on fixed doctrines and clear taxonomies, seem to slip through our fingers when trying to grasp Shinto&amp;rsquo;s essential nature. Yet rather than viewing this resistance as a barrier to understanding, we might see it as a window into Shinto&amp;rsquo;s unique character.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Getting married in Japan</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/japanesemarriage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/articles/japanesemarriage/</guid><description>&lt;div class="pagedescription">I’m a UK citizen, and I recently married another UK citizen in Tokyo while we were on holiday. If you&amp;rsquo;re planning to do the same, here’s a detailed guide to help you through the process. It will involve the preparation of some translations before you travel, a trip to the British Embassy in Tokyo (pre-booked), and at least one visit to a municpal office in Japan that deals with the registration of births, marriages, deaths, and divorces &amp;mdash; I recommend two visits.&lt;/div>
&lt;h1 id="before-you-travel-to-japan">Before you travel to Japan&lt;/h1>
&lt;section >
&lt;h2 id="step-1-book-an-appointment-at-the-british-embassy">Step 1: Book an appointment at the British Embassy&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Japanese authorities will require a document that&amp;rsquo;s equivalent to the &lt;strong>Certificate of No Impediment&lt;/strong>, known as a 婚姻要件具備証明書 (Kon-In yōken gubi shōmei sho). In our case, this was an affidavit provided by the British Embassy.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>