<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>arts on The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/arts/</link><description>Recent content in arts on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/arts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Klee's Line</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/kleesline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/kleesline/</guid><description>Paul Klee called drawing, &amp;lsquo;Taking a line for a walk&amp;rsquo; and ever since I first saw his drawings I&amp;rsquo;ve been really taken with the quality of his line.
Paul Klee, &amp;lsquo;They&amp;rsquo;re Biting&amp;rsquo;
I just assumed he&amp;rsquo;d drawn in ink on &amp;ndash; possibly&amp;ndash; damp paper, which I thought would explain the bleeding of the line and it&amp;rsquo;s smudginess. I tried to mimic it again and again, with scratchy-nibbed dip-pens, different weights and finishes of paper; and I never got there.</description></item><item><title>Pomostmodern murder</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/pomomurder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/pomomurder/</guid><description>I once complained to the small clique in control of a student magazine that they&amp;rsquo;d devoted an entire issue to semiological analyses of, variously, clothes, cinema and music. &amp;ldquo;And have you actually read anything about semiology?&amp;rdquo; sneered one?
I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really and the criticism smarted so I went off to learn about semiology. And then postmodernism. I quite liked some Roland Barthes. I read Jonathan Culler on deconstruction &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;On Deconstruction&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; and I read Derrida, and Baudrillard, and de Man, and Foucault, and Lacan, and more.</description></item><item><title>World Poetry Day</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/worldpoetryday/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 17:00:22 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/worldpoetryday/</guid><description>A belated post catching up on World Poetry Day. Here are two nominations, both inspired by Ancient Greece, the first contemporary and the second around 2,000 years old.
Alice Oswald, Memorial My most recent discovery and keeper has been Alice Oswald - especially &amp;lsquo;Memorial&amp;rsquo;, a retelling of the Iliad with only the deaths left in. She was trained as a classicist and sometimes calls this a translation, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t. It&amp;rsquo;s an original work inspired by Homer.</description></item><item><title>Ancient Greek literature: it's really rather good</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/ancientgreeklit/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/03/ancientgreeklit/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a longtime fan of the Iliad &amp;ndash; I think one of my old primary school teachers must have read a version to my class when I was an infant because I seem to have known the stories forever. The judgement of Paris, the elopement of Helen, the becalming of the Greek ships and the sacrifice of Iphignia, and so on. I have listened, rapt, to an hour-long lecture devoted to the very first line:</description></item><item><title>Pronouncing Don Quixote in La Mancha</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2016/11/donquixote/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2016 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2016/11/donquixote/</guid><description>Pizarro in the market square of Trujillo, Spain
On holiday in Spain in 2007 I read Don Quixote — and ploughing through some parts in the Don’s homeland, the region of La Mancha, I thought I’d solved the puzzle of the protagonist’s name: Key-Ho-Tay or Kwiksot?
I’ve previously spoken the name ‘Don Quixote’ as Don Key-ho-tay although of course I’ve been aware of the alternative Don Quick-Sot. The version of the novel I had, the translation by John Rutherford (winner of the 2002 Primo Valle Inclàn Prize) definitely plumps for Kwiksot in its rhymes.</description></item></channel></rss>