<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>computing on The website of David Jones</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/computing/</link><description>Recent content in computing on The website of David Jones</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 06:00:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/tags/computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bindicator - an Alexa skill for bin collections</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/06/bindicate/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/06/bindicate/</guid><description>A Glasgow-based IT consultant who developed a little bin-shaped device that lights-up with different colours to indicate which bins are due for collection prompted me to do something similar with Alexa and AWS lambdas. It’s essentially free, and free is good.
Introduction Can’t remember which bins to put out? This is a quick look at an Alexa skill I’ve developed that uses my local council’s website as a source of information about bin collections, and lets me ask Alexa when my next bin collection is, and what bins are being collected, and when any particular bin is next being collected.</description></item><item><title>The Unbearable Lightness of Being on Social Media</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/unbearablelightness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/unbearablelightness/</guid><description>The memory throws up high and dry A crowd of twisted things; &amp;mdash; Eliot, 'Rhapsody on a Windy Night' Vicky Lai&amp;rsquo;s recent blog post about deleting older tweets, using an AWS lambda, struck a deep chord with me and I&amp;rsquo;ve implemented her ephemeral solution. Description of technical fix over at Vicky&amp;rsquo;s blog and my take on it below.
Vicky believes that social media imposes a view of identity that&amp;rsquo;s new &amp;ndash; and innacurate.</description></item><item><title>A little network issue</title><link>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/network/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 06:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://thisisdavidjones.github.io/blog/2018/04/network/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m experimenting with cheap-and-cheerful voice control of my music system. I have a NAS with tens of thousands of ripped music files and I&amp;rsquo;d like to play them, easily, on my Sonos speakers and/or my Echo Dots.
The salient bits of my home network
Now I could upload them to some subscription service, and use the streaming capabilities - but it seems to me a bad idea for three reasons:</description></item></channel></rss>